Edwin Espinoza

(760) 215-0969 • espined48@gmail.com • edwin-espinoza.com

Professional Summary

Web developer with experience building RESTful applications. Many different skills from LAMP stack to MEAN stack. Created full application with user authentication using passport and full database support using MongoDB. Familiar with many common JavaScript libraries.

Education

Humboldt State University - Arcata, CA

Bachelor's Degree: 2020

B.S. Computer Science with Honors

Applied Mathematics Minor

San Marcos High School - San Marcos, CA

High school diploma: 2012

<u>Accomplishments</u>

- Helped establish a coding club in the after school program at Zane Middle School in Eureka, CA, which led to the program getting a grant.
- Research Experience for Undergraduates funded by the National Science Foundation, I conducted research on kernel level malware detection on Linux systems.

Skills & Languages

- Self-motivated
- Oracle SQL, Linux, PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS
- Java, C++
- Bootstrap, Mongodb, Nodejs, Semantic UI
- English
- Spanish
- American sign language

Work History

General Tutor, 08/2018 to 06/2020

Humboldt State University – Arcata, CA

- I would drive to different school sites that have TRIO Talent Search students.
- Be able to work without supervision and help students with math.
- Ran a coding club at one of the local middle schools.
- Held structured meetings to discuss STEM summer programs to get students interested in STEM fields, as well as developed lessons and lesson plans for students.

Computer Science Tutor, 01/2019 to 05/2020

Humboldt State University – Arcata, CA

- Helped university students with their assignments and understanding of computer science concepts.
- Responsible for tracking student usage of tutoring services, and creating a friendly and studious environment for students to work in.

Math Tutor, 06/2016 to 08/2018

Palomar Community College District – San Marcos, CA

- I had to learn and understand the many different backgrounds and cultures.
- Manage time with the students.

References

Dr. Richard Sauerheber: Co-worker, Tutor, Researcher, Ph.D. Chemistry from University of CA, San Diego

Phone: (760) 744-1150 x2448E-mail: rsauerheber@palomar.edu

Dr. Bori Mazzag: Supervisor, Chair of Mathematics & Computer Science Ph.D. Applied Mathematics from University of CA, Davis

Phone: (707) 826-4952E-mail: borim@humboldt.edu

Rose Sita Francia: Supervisor, M.A. in Educational Leadership, TRIO Talent Search Director and Collaboration Lead

• Phone: (707) 826-4791

• E-mail: rose.francia@humboldt.edu